Briefly_

I have cultivated the passions for computer science and music since the age of 5. I have a training as a computer scientist, acquired between universities in Italy, Sweden and Singapore. Now, in the context of a PhD, I am specializing in Machine Learning, participating to different projects in parallel, and acquiring a more comprehensive approach to design thinking. Recently, following my need to give a broader sense to my profession, I am approaching the world of green entrepreneurship.

Education

PhD in Computer Science and Mathematics

Ferrara, Italy

University of Parma

11/2020 - Present

- · Topics: interpretable machine learning, computer vision, time series classification, data science, efficient and parallel computing
- My main research line aims at the formalization of *modal symbolic learning*, a novel methodology for obtaining *interpretable* intelligent models for computer vision and spatial/temporal pattern recognition
- I'm working on various projects for testing the effectiveness of new machine learning methods: COVID-19 diagnosis from cough/breath sounds; EEG signal interpretation; gas turbine trip prevention; land cover classification from satellite imagery 🐉

Master Degree in Computer Science

Gothenburg, Sweden

University of Gothenburg

08/2018 - 06/2020

- ECTS: 120. GRADE: G
- TOPICS: machine learning, computer vision, bioinformatics, discrete optimization, logic, compilers
- THESIS: Interactionwise Semantic Awareness for Visual Relationship Detection
- I enrolled into an student exchange program (6 months), which took me to the *National University of Singapore (NUS)*, where I deepend my knowledge on computer vision

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science

Ferrara, Italy

University of Ferrara

09/2015 - 07/2018

- ECTS: 180, Grade: 110/110 with honors
- · Topics: algorithms, computability and complexity theory, parallel computing, computer architecture, operating systems
- THESIS: Optimization of Lattice Boltzmann simulations for Intel Xeon Phi 'Knights Landing'

Experience_

Findwise ABGothenburg, Sweden

MACHINE LEARNING DEVELOPER - MASTER THESIS WORK

01/2020 - 06/2020

- I tackled a problem of detection of interactions between objects in digital images (Visual Relationship Detection)
- I made extensive use of machine learning techniques for computer vision and natural language processing (NLP)

University of Gothenburg

Gothenburg, Sweden

TEACHING ASSISTANT (COURSE: Algorithms I)

01/2020 - 03/2020

• I graded home assignments and held a few excercise sessions

University of Ferrara

Ferrara, Italy

RESEARCH TRAINEE - BACHELOR THESIS WORK

09/2017 - 06/2018

- I optimized a C code for fluid dynamics simulations, targeting highly-parallel architectures
- I measured performance of different data layouts and memory access patterns

Mercato delle Terre Estensi

IT TECHNICIAN

Ferrara, Italy 01/2016 - 08/2018

• I Built a website and a management/billing system in HTML/PHP/CSS/Javascript

Technical skills

Machine learningpytorch, computer vision, natural language processingOS & task automationLinux programming, UNIX shell, data processing & cleaning

Functional Julia, Haskell **Object-oriented** C++, Java, Python

Low-level C (parallel computing with MPI, OpenMP, pthread, CUDA), LLVM

Full-stack MySQL, PHP, Javascript

Other ETFX, Matlab, R, Go (basic knowledge), Linear programming

Relevant projects

Modal Decision Trees in Julia 🖸 🛗

University of Ferrara

Framework for interpretable classification of data with dimensional components, such as audio recordings, images, videos, and EEG signals. Presented at JuliaCon2022.

202

Transparent COVID-19 diagnosis from audio samples of breath and cough

University of Ferrara

Modal decision trees allow the extraction of knowledge in *explicit* form, able to explain the relation between vocal patterns in cough/breath samples and the presence of COVID-19 in a human subject.

2020

Pitòn - Rule extraction from MySQL databases 🖸

Class Semantic Awareness for neural networks

University of Ferrara

Laravel Package (PHP) for training rule-based classification models from data stored in MySQL databases.

University of Gothenburg

Attempt at improving the standard softmax-based classification framework for neural networks.

2020

Dimensionality reduction: a performance comparison of PCA, LDA and FJLT 🖸 🖺

National University of Singapore

2019

EasyG - Classifying Electrocardiograms using deep learning 🖸 🖺

University of Gothenburg

2019

2020

Languages

Italian Native speaker

English IELTS Academic score: 7.0

Personal interests

Learning Touch typing, ergonomics, codes, languages

Music Arrangement, Professional studies of jazz guitar and piano

Entertainment Video-editing, improv **Sport** Climbing, table tennis

Honors & awards

2022 **Winner**, MAGICA Summer School, Acceleration Programme

2021 Finalist, Huawei Italy University Challenge

Participant, Talents for Open Innovation

TV & news appearance, Focus on a Research work I conducted on TV program "Oggi è un Altro Giorno"

Personal Data

In compliance with the GDPR and Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize the recipient of this document to use and process my personal details for the purpose of recruiting and selecting staff and I confirm to be informed of my rights in accordance to art. 7 of the above mentioned decree.